Richard Wilkosz

Software Engineer

Phone

715-370-8005

Email

richard.w.wilkosz@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/richard-wilkosz-026b4715a

GitHub

github.com/richardwilkosz

Website

richardwilkosz.com

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End

JavaScript	
ES6 / TypeScript	
Vue.js	
Angular	
JQuery	
REST API integration	
HTML / CSS	
SCSS / SASS	
Bootstrap	

Back End

C#

Python	•00
SQL	
Cloud / BaaS	lacktriangle

UX Design

Responsive design	
Accessibility design	
Wireframing	
Usability testing	

Project Management

Git	
Jira / Confluence	
Agile / Scrum	
Unit testing	

SAMPLE PROJECT

Check out Ray, my database of movies I own on Blu-ray! It features Vue.js, REST API consumption, and responsive design: richardwilkosz.com

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience writing production-level code. Specializes in user-centered front ends, but delivers clean and reusable full-stack code. In the past year, has demonstrated leadership and communication skills by serving as team Scrum Master and mentoring 7+ interns.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Apr 2021 – Present Software Engineer Sentry Insurance

- Designs and implements web application to replace vendor system with millions of data rows. Back end features C# / SQL batch processes with over 70% test coverage. Front end features CRUD data tables and Material Design SCSS framework.
- Mentors 5 interns for the 2021 summer program. Meets weekly to address technical and company-related questions. Coordinates social events and guest speakers to foster connections.

Jan 2020-Mar 2021 Software Developer Sentry Insurance

• Digitized the company's 2020 United Way donation campaign with a C# web application, processing nearly 4500 transactions.

- Delivered employee health information system, replacing a PeopleSoft component with a C# web application.
- Designed and implemented new front end components for 4 legacy systems, including systems owned by other teams.
- Served as team Scrum Master for over 1 year. Led daily meetings, tracked development progress, and communicated milestones and course corrections to management.

May 2018– Dec 2019 **Associate Software Developer (Internship)**

Sentry Insurance

- Created functional Angular prototype of an administration page for call flow automation. Conducted 3 user interviews to inform the design and presented the prototype to department executives.
- Delivered C# web application to replace legacy mainframe system, featuring C# / SQL batch processes and CRUD data tables.

Oct 2017-Dec 2019 **Technology Tutor, Writing Tutor**University of Wisconsin-Stevens Point

- Tutored 50+ peers in Computer Science courses: Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, and more.
- Tutored 30+ peers in written communication, including business proposals and technical documents.

EDUCATION

Dec 2019

B.S. Computer Information SystemsUniversity of Wisconsin–Stevens Point

- Double majored in Web Development.
- Graduated summa cum laude.